rentals.ca 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy | Rentals.ca

The privacy of our clients and users is very important to the team at Rentals.ca. We wish to always be open an upfront about what information we collect from you, a user of our website, and about how that information is used. 

Rentals.ca operates a website that allows people to list or locate apartments, houses or other real estate for rent online (Service), and makes it available to you, the user, subject to our Terms of Use. 

This Privacy Policy describes how the information you provide to us, or that we learn from you through the Service, is collected, used and disclosed. If you don't want your information collected, used or disclosed in the way outlined in this policy, please do not use the Service. 

### The Information We Collect

User-Provided Information: We may collect personal identification information from users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when a user visits our site, registers for an account, places an order, subscribes to our newsletter, or fills out a form. We may also collect this information in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Rentals.ca. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, their name, email address, mailing address, phone number and credit card information. Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously, should they wish to not provide personal identification information. We will collect personal identification information from users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personal identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain activities related to the site. 

Non-Personal Identification Information: We may collect data, which is data from which individual identifiers have been removed, during your use of the site. For example, information about how you use the Service may be combined with information about how others use it, without any personal information being recorded in the resulting data. 

Cookies: When you use the Service, we may send cookies to your computer’s hard drive. Cookies sometimes track information about your use of our site and Service, and provides Rentals.ca with information that may include the user’s browser type, computer or OS type, Internet Service Provider and technical information about how the user connects to our site. 

Automatically Collected Information: When you use Rentals.ca, some information from your web browser or mobile device may be automatically stored. This automatically collected information includes your Internet Protocol address, the type of mobile device you use, web browser type, a record of websites that you visit before or after the Service, the pages you view, and the dates and times that you use the Service. We employ analytics companies to use tracking technologies that collect information about our users’ computers or mobile devices and their online activities. These companies analyze the data so we can better understand how our Service is being used. 

Third-Party Links: We may include links and buttons to third parties (such as Facebook “like” or “share” buttons or Twitter “tweet” buttons) and links to external websites on our site, including links to property management companies’ websites, or other websites. These links and external sites and services might collect information about you and your internet activities through cookies – even if you do not click the button or link. Information collected through buttons is collected directly by these third parties without our participation. The manner of use of information collected by a third party in this fashion falls under that third party’s data collection, use and disclosure policies. 

Integrated Services: You might have the option to register with Rentals.ca through a third party's service, such as a Facebook or Google account. If you agree to register in this manner, you authorize the Integrated Service to send us and allow us to store personal information and other information about you. Please review the privacy policies and terms and conditions of these integrated services. 

Location Information: Rentals.ca includes features that allow us to access information about your location. On a web browser, you might have to enable settings that allow us to read your location, while on a mobile device, your settings could allow us to access your location automatically. These settings can be changed on your mobile device or web browser in order to disallow us from recording your location. We may also access your location using your IP address, through geo-fencing technology, or other available means. 

### How Rentals.ca Uses This Information

We might collect and use your personal information for the following purposes: 

Making our Service Available to You: We use your email address to notify you about news and updates about our Service, to respond to your queries sent to us, and to send you other types of information. We might store and refer to communications from you to Rentals.ca to help us serve you better. We may monitor communications to identify and remove users who try to make fraudulent transactions, scam other users or engage in illegal activities. 

Always Improving: We might use information collected from you, the user, to improve our marketing and promotional activities, to better understand users' preferences about the way Rentals.ca looks and operates, and to develop new features to serve our users. 

Customizing the Service: We may use automatically collected data and cookies to remember information you already provided to use to you don't have to enter it again on your next visit to our Service. We may also use your information to provide ads, promotions, content and information that are personalized to your preferences and usage of our Service, and additionally to analyze the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. We might also use any location information you provide to determine the effectiveness of our Service. 

Processing Payments: We might use personal information you provide to us to process payments when you place an order. We do not share this information with third parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service. 

Fulfilling Your Requests: We may send your information, provided to TorontoRentals.com, to third parties to fulfill user request, such as if you reply to a listing for a third party's service or product, or if you sign up to receive notifications about rental listings from that third party or other third parties. In such cases, we will provide some of your personal information to the related third parties in order to fulfill your request. Please be aware: Our Privacy Policy does not apply to third parties, who may handle your personal information in a different manner than described in this Privacy Policy. You should check the Privacy Policy of each third party that would have access to your personal information to gain an understanding of how your information could be used, stored and disclosed. 

Operating our Service: TorontoRentals.com could disclose personally identifiable and automatically collected information to third parties to process that information on our behalf, to provide website services, maintenance, and security, to manage our contacts and send out promotional messages on our behalf, to help us improve the way our Service works and looks, and to create new features. 

Aggregate Data: We may share automatically collected and aggregate data with interested third parties so they can analyze the interest and usage patterns for certain information, products, services, data, content, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on our Service. 

Legal Obligations: We may disclose personal information when we believe that doing so fulfills our legal requirement, or would protect our property or legal rights, or to protect the property and rights of others. 

Third-Party Marketing: If you express interest in being contacted regarding certain features, information or services related to our Service, we may sell or give access to your information to third parties in order to fulfill that interest in a particular feature, information or service, or to that of a related third party. 

Change in Control: Information about our users may be disclosed or transferred as part of a merger, acquisition, debt financing, or sale of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personally identifiable information is transferred to third parties as one of our business assets. 

Public Areas: Information that you include in a publicly accessible area of the Service will be available to anyone who has access to that content, including other users. We cannot control who reads your posting or what other users may do with the information you voluntarily post, so we encourage you to exercise discretion and caution with respect to what you share through the Service. 

Google AdSense: Some of the ads that appear on our Site may be served by Google. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the internet. DART uses 'non-personally identifiable information' and does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, etc. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html 

### How Your Information Is Protected

Rentals.ca does not sell, trade, or rent Users' personal identification information to other parties. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy. We may use third-party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes, provided that you have given us your permission. 

Your Account and Password: You can always choose not to share personal information with Rentals.ca, however we may not be able to provide you with all the features of our Service. You can ask us to delete your information from our active user databases by contacting us at the address at the bottom of this page, in which case we will use commercially reasonable efforts to do so. Please note that while such deletions may be reflected in our active user databases, we may retain your personal information for a variety of other purposes, including backups and archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, and analytics. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access to your account for the Service. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times. 

Emails: You can unsubscribe from promotional and update emails from Rentals.ca by following the instructions in the email. However, even if you do unsubscribe, you may still receive some administrative emails from us. 

### Our Commitment to Data Security

Sending data over the internet is never 100% secure. While we take reasonable steps to protect information you send to us via our Service, you do so at your own risk. Please note that we cannot completely guarantee that your information will never be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by firewall or secure server software breach. 

If we learn of a security systems breach, we may try to notify you electronically so you can take action to protect your information. By using our Service or sending us your personal information, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to the Service. We may post a notice on our website if a security breach occurs, or we may email you a notification to the email address you provide to us. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. 

### A Notice To International Users

Rentals.ca's Service is hosted in Canada. For users who access our Service from outside of Canada, please note that you are transferring your personal data outside your home jurisdiction. By providing your personal data you consent to Rentals.ca’s use of your personal data for the purposes laid our in this Privacy Policy. 

### Changes To This Privacy Policy

Rentals.ca reserves the discretion to update this Privacy Policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. 

### Your Acceptance Of These Terms

By using Rentals.ca, you signify your acceptance of this policy and the site’s Terms of Use. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes. 

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at: 

Rentals.ca

900 Lady Ellen Pl Suite 216

Ottawa, ON, Canada
